In today's video, we are going to be
introduced
to dynamics. First of all, what are
dynamics?
In physics, dynamics are the study of
motion
and, more particularly, forces.
The difference between dynamics and
kinematics
is that in kinematics, we study about
motion
itself, while in dynamics, we study how
and
what causes the motion. For example, if
someone
pushes a box, we would be studying the
force
that the person exerts onto this box that
makes
the box move. And this directly correlates
into my next subject about Newton's laws.
So I'll be introducing Newton's three laws
right
now, and these basically govern what we
know
about movement, motion, and dynamics
itself.
First of all, an object that is at rest
stays
at rest and a moving object stays in
motion
until a net external force is acted on it.
So what does that mean? Well, basically,
anything
that has a velocity or is moving will keep
that
velocity until a force is acted upon it.
What does this mean? This means that
forces
are the only thing that can move an
object.
Nothing else can cause an object to move.
And you might be wondering, well, if I
roll
a ball, why does it slow down? Well,
that's
because there's actually a friction force
acting
upon it. There always is a force that
makes
an object do what it does in motion, and
this
friction force has two components. We'll
talk
about that later. Next, the acceleration
of
an object is directly proportional to the
what this is saying is acceleration is the
net
force over mass, inversely proportional to
mass
and directly proportional to net force.
And with this, we can get our first
formula,
probably arguably the most important
formula
in high school physics.
F net equals acceleration times mass or
MA,
and this is a really important formula.
So this basically describes and
demonstrates
how a force can induce movement and
acceleration,
and it's purely based off of its mass and
the
force given. And for every action, there
is
an equal and opposite reaction. This is
also
a really, really important law, and it's
quizzed
a lot of times. And of course, you might
be
very, very familiar with this law, but it
is
also good to remember. If you, let's say,
punch
a block of wood, that wood is going to
exert
the same force as your fist does on your
hand.
If you catch a baseball, let's say, if you
catch
a baseball with your hand, that baseball
is
going to exert the same amount of force as
it
does, as your hand does on the baseball.
And that's basically the third law, and
it's
really useful for a lot of thinking
questions.
And these are very, very important laws.
They basically make up what we know about
dynamics,
and they're the foundation for the
introduction.
We derive most of our formulas from these
laws,
and I'll get into that later.